

# Carlos José **Cortés Rivera**

Java Developer, Scrum Master, and Project Manager

## Profile

Electronic Engineer of the University of Antioquia, with skills in analog and digital electronics, trained in software development under agile methodology performs in roles like Scrum Master and Scrum developer. I have knowledge related to Linux command line, JIRA, Confluence, BitBucket, and languages like C, C++, GraphQL, and Kotlin, mainly knowledge in Java 8, 11 with Spring framework and Spring Boot. E-commerce with InterShop, WordPress, Angular 9, and basic knowledge of AngularJS. Additionally, experience leading development teams in project implementations.

I am a friendly person, like to interact, share, and learn from others. Passionate for help to my team improve their technicals and humans skills.



## Employment History

#### Java Developer at InAllMedia

May 2021 — current

- Web Application development implementing new features for Indeed in Featured Employer area, working using Java 8, GraphQL nd PostgresQL databases.

#### Java Developer at Globant, Medellín

March 2021 — May 2022

- Web applications development using microservices with Spring Boot, Kotlin, and Java 11 with PostgresQL Databases.

## Software development analyst at SoftCaribbean,

Medellín August 2020 — March 2021

Functions:

- Web and mobile applications development using Java 11, Angular 9 and Ionic, and MySQL Databases.

#### Project analyst at Cadena Apps, La Estrella

August 2019 — July 20

Functions:

Project management with SCRUM agile methodology.

- Requirements gathering identifying the client's needs.
- Help development teams detecting and removing impediments or stoppers in the implementations.

## Software development analyst at Cadena Apps, La Estrella August 2017 — July 2019

Functions:

- Development and support of Web applications with Spring framework and Spring Boot.
- Development and support of B2B and B2C E-commerce developer with InterShop Framework based on Java.

## Maintenance Engineer at CRYSTAL S.A.S., Sabaneta

June 2016 — July 2017

Functions:

- Monitoring system support of the clothing manufacture process. - Projects Management related to the clothing manufacture process.

#### Mechatronic apprentice at CRYSTAL S.A.S.,

Sabaneta November 2015 — May 2016

Functions:

- Monitoring system support of the socks factoring process.
- Implement new functionalities on the monitoring system of the socks factoring process, for example, new firmware remote update of the system.

#### Development auxiliary at University of Antioquia,

Medellín April 2015 — October 2015

Functions:

- Maintenance and monitoring with the laboratory machines.
- Repair any kind of Bug or incident of the laboratory machines.
- Server support of the laboratory servers.

#### **Details**

Calle 10 C # 10-26 Int 201, Girardota - Antioquia, Colombia +57-3107360279 carlojo4@gmail.com

Date / Place of birth

26 - June - 1993 Itagüí - Antioquia

Links

Carlos Cortés - LinkedIn

#### Skills

Java 11 Apache Tomcat

Java 8 Apache

Kotlin C++

GraphQL

Angular 9 Git Flow

Spring Boot Javascript

Microservices Jenkins

Agile and Scrum Languages

Agile Project Management JIRA English

Confluence Spanish

## Education

## Electronic Engineering, University of Antioquia, Medellín

May 2010 — September 2016

#### Scrum Master Professional Certificate, IT Service, Medellín

February 2020 — February 2020 CertiProf ID: 81580861447354

## Scrum Product Owner Professional Certificate, IT Service, Medellín

February 2020 — February 2020 CertiProf ID: 71580950721057

## Scrum Product Owner Professional Certificate, IT Service, Medellín

February 2020 — February 2020 CertiProf ID: 71580950721057

## Oracle Certified Professional: Java SE 11 Developer, ORACLE

April 2021

**Badge** 

## **™** References

#### **Daniel Villegas Salazar from OneLink BPO**

+57-3104605121

## Mateo Gómez Díaz from Simple Solutions S.A.S.

mateogomezd@gmail.com · +57-3014134391

## Álvaro López Gonzalez from Source Meridian

elvaro97@gmail.com · +57-3016972036